Guide to the Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, Office of the Dean records, 1911-2006 UA.25.02.0001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, Office of the Dean records
1911-2006
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences. Office of the Dean
UA.25.02.0001
259 Linear Feet
The Dean of Trinity College of Arts and Sciences is the University's principal spokesperson for the needs of undergraduate education. The Dean is involved in the processes of academic budgeting and in the appointment, promotion and retention of faculty. The collection contains correspondence, reports, brochures, pamphlets, booklets, meeting minutes and meeting agendas, in addition to Course Synopsis Handbooks. There are also clippings and articles that relate to broad topics such as trends in faculty salaries and student populations. Dates range from 1911-2006.
Access Restrictions
For a period of twenty-five years from the origin of the material, permission in writing from the office of origin and the University Archivist is required for use. After twenty-five years, records that have been processed may be consulted with the permission of the University Archivist.
Provenance
The Trinity College of Arts and Sciences, Office of the Dean records were received by the University Archives as a series of transfers between 1962-2019.
Biographical/Historical note
The Dean of Trinity College of Arts and Sciences is the University's principal spokesperson for the needs of undergraduate education. The Dean is involved in the processes of academic budgeting and in the appointment, promotion and retention of faculty. The Dean serves as the principal information source for current developments in undergraduate education along with the faculty, provides new ideas about curricular enrichment. Historically, the Dean has served as a presiding officer of the UFCAS, appointed Directors of Undergraduate Studies and of Freshman Studies, appointed faculty advisors for freshmen, served as a member of the Committee on Promotion and Tenure and participated directly in the selection of department chairs.
Scope and Contents note
Collection contains correspondence, reports, brochures, pamphlets, booklets, meeting minutes, and meeting agendas, in addition to Course Synopsis Handbooks. There are also clippings and articles that relate to broad topics such as trends in faculty salaries and student populations. The 2019 accession includes staff meeting minutes, reports, and materials from the Curriculum Committee.
Related Material
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Reference Collection, University Archives
Duke University Archives
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Small Collections, University Archives
Duke University Archives
Trinity College of Arts and Sciences Subject Collections, Duke University Archives
Duke University Archives
Conditions Governing Access
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
Conditions Governing Access
Portions of these materials are restricted by donor request.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials have not been screened for sensitive or restricted content. Staff may need to screen materials before use. Please contact Research Services for more information.
Financial statements; Committees; Departments, Academic; Curriculum planning; Duke University -- Administration; Duke University -- Admission; Duke University -- History -- 20th century; Duke University -- Periodicals; Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences. Office of the Dean; Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences; Duke University. Air Force Reserve Officers' Training Corps; Duke University -- Students; Duke University. Trinity College of Arts and Sciences -- Funds and scholarships; Duke University. Board of Trustees
- Container List
  - Cranford, William Ivey: Correspondence, 1911-1917 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Advisory Committee, 1961-1964 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Analysis, Summer and Fall, 1950-1955 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Policy Committee, 1955-1959 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Reports - Trinity College and the College of Engineering, 1949-1950 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Reports - Women's College Fall, 1950-1953 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Studies, 1956-1958 (Box 1)
  - Admissions: Trends, 1948-1953 (Box 1)
  - Commonwealth Studies: Account Book - New Fund (Box 1)
  - Commonwealth Studies: Account Book - Old Fund (Box 1)
  - Commonwealth Studies: Account Book - Ford Foundation, International Relations (Box 1)
  - Commonwealth Studies: Account Book - Ford Foundation, International Relations and National Defense Education Act, NDEA (Box 1)
  - Socio-Economic Studies of Aging: Account Book - Ford Foundation, 1956-1961 (Box 1)
  - Ford International Relations Grant: Account Book, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Administrative and Miscellaneous Projects (Box 1)
  - African Studies Projects (Box 1)
  - Asian Areas Fund (Box 1)
  - Authorizations: All Codes, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
  - Authorizations: All Codes, Pending and Continuing (Box 1)
  - Authorizations: Commonwealth Studies, 1955-1959 (Box 1)
  - Authorizations: Directed to Dean Lewis and Mrs. Cooper, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Authorizations: New Fund, 1959 September 1-1965 September 1 (Box 1)
  - British Commonwealth Project (Box 1)
  - Budgets, 1964-1967 (Box 1)
  - Canada Trip, 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Canadian Conference of Learned Societies Meeting, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Carnegie Commonwealth Studies: Financial Report, 1955-1968 (Box 2)
  - Carnegie Commonwealth Studies: IBM Financial Statements, 1955-1965 (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Project Committee, 1954-1955 (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Studies Center, 1955-1962 (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Studies Committee Minutes, 1954-1966 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 2)
  - Commonwealth Studies: Projects, 1965-1967 (Box 2)
  - Comparative Institutions: IBM Financial Statements, 1965-1966 (Box 2)
  - Comparative Institutions: Projects (Box 2)
  - Ford Commonwealth Studies: Grant IBM Financial Statements, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Ford Commonwealth Studies: International Relations - Codes (Box 3)
  - Ford Commonwealth Studies: International Relations - Executive Committee, 1961-1965 (Box 3)
  - Ford Commonwealth Studies: International Relations - Financial Report, 1963-1967 (Box 3)
  - Ford Commonwealth Studies: International Relations - IBM Financial Statements, 1962-1968 (Box 3)
  - Ford Foundation Grants and Sub-Grants - IBM Financial Statements, 1965-1967 (Box 3)
  - Commonwealth Studies: International Relations Minutes, 1965-1969 (Box 3)
  - Socio-Economic Studies of Aging, 1959-1965 (Box 3)
  - Hispanic Council: Projects, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Library Program of the Commonwealth Studies Center (Box 3)
  - List of Selected Official Publications and Serials of the British Commonwealth in the Duke University Library, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Sub-Committee Minutes, 1962-1966 (Box 3)
  - Monthly Financial Breakdowns and Cumulative Summaries, 1955-1965 (Box 3)
  - NDEA Financial Reports and IBM Statements, 1964-1968 (Box 3)
  - Parent Grant (Box 3)
  - Pre-Doctoral Grants: Awarded Authorizations, 1965-1967 (Box 3)
  - Professional Training: Projects (Box 3)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Grant: IBM Financial Statements, 1964-1966 (Box 3)
  - Seminar: Divinity School, 1964 April (Box 3)
  - Seminar: School of Forestry, 1964 (Box 3)
  - South Asian Studies: Projects (Box 3)
  - Southern Regional Education Board: Post-Doctoral Training Program, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Study of Ideas: Projects (Box 3)
  - Summer Conference of the Commonwealth Studies Committee, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Summer Seminars Fund: Medical (Box 3)
  - Washington Trip of Manchester, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Aesthetics, Art and Music, 1953-1954 (Box 3)
  - Botany: Analysis (Box 4)
  - Chemistry (Box 4)
  - Classical Studies (Box 4)
  - Economics (Box 4)
  - Education (Box 4)
  - English, circa 1949-1958 (Box 4)
  - Geology (Box 4)
  - German (Box 4)
  - Greek (Box 4)
  - History, 1957-1960 (Box 4)
  - History, 1949-1956 (Box 4)
  - Latin (Box 4)
  - Mathematics (Box 4)
  - Nursing School: Budget (Box 4)
  - Nursing School, 1951-1956 (Box 4)
  - Physical Education (Box 4)
  - Physics (Box 4)
  - Political Science (Box 4)
  - Psychology (Box 4)
  - Religion (Box 4)
  - Romance Language (Box 4)
  - Russian, 1958-1959 (Box 4)
  - Sociology (Box 4)
  - Zoology (Box 4)
  - Departmental Budgets, 1959-1960 (Box 4)
  - Enrollment Estimates: Department Requests and Analysis, 1950-1953 Fall (Box 5)
  - Space Assignments, 1950 and 1953 (Box 5)
  - Staff Requests by Departments: Aesthetics - History, 1954-1959 (Box 5)
  - Actual Enrollment, 1950-1959 *Contains restricted information (Box 5)
  - Attrition Studies, 1934-1959 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 5)
  - Class Census Reports, 1959-1960 (Box 5)
  - College of Engineering: Enrollment and Staff, 1950-1954 (Box 5)
  - Enrollment Estimates, 1948-1958 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 5)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1950-1957 (Box 5)
  - Freshmen Orientation, 1951 September (Box 5)
  - Gergen Committee: Enrollment Study, 1949-1955 (Box 5)
  - Orientation: Preliminaries, 1949 September (Box 5)
  - Pre-Enrollment Figures, 1953-1958 (Box 5)
  - Pre-Registration, 1954-1958 (Box 5)
  - Registration, 1950-1958 (Box 5)
  - Registration and Orientation: Plans, 1948-1958 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 5)
  - Statistics, 1949-1958 (Box 5)
  - Enrollment Estimates, 1949 August-October (Box 6)
  - Enrollment Estimates, 1949 May-July (Box 6)
  - Enrollment Estimates, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Enrollment Estimates, Nursing School, 1956 Fall (Box 6)
  - Enrollment Estimates, Study of Normal Distribution of Classes, 1950 April 5 (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1957 (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1956 Fall (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1955 Fall (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1954 Fall (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1953 Fall (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1951 Fall (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment by Departments, 1950 Fall (Box 6)
  - Estimated Need vs. Actual Enrollment, 1950 Fall (Box 6)
  - Freshman Orientation, 1951 September (Box 6)
  - Gergen Committee, Enrollment Study, 1949-1955 (Box 6)
  - Orientation, Preliminaries, 1949 September (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1958 Fall (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1957-1958 Spring (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1957 Fall (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1956-1957 Spring (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1955-1956 (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1954 Fall (Box 6)
  - Pre-enrollment Figures, 1953-1954 Spring (Box 6)
  - Pre-registration, 1958 Fall (Box 6)
  - Pre-registration, 1956 Spring (Box 6)
  - Registration, Dean Hobbs' study, 1956 (Box 6)
  - Registration, Figures, 1950 January (Box 6)
  - Registration, Figures and Plans, 1956-1957 Fall (Box 6)
  - Registration, Plans, 1958 Spring (Box 6)
  - Registration, pre-enrollment, 1950 Summer and Fall (Box 6)
  - Registration, Programs, 1954-1957 (Box 6)
  - Registration and orientation, plans, 1948-1949 (Box 6)
  - Registration and orientation, plans, 1950-1951 (Box 6)
  - Registration and orientation, plans, 1957 Fall (Box 6)
  - Registration and orientation, plans, 1958 Fall *Contains restricted information (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1949 Fall (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1950 Fall (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1951-1952 (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1952 Fall (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1953 Spring (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1953 Fall (Box 6)
  - Statistics, 1954 Spring (Box 6)
  - Statistics, annual report, 1956-1957 (Box 6)
  - Statistics, annual report, 1957-1958 (Box 6)
  - Statistics, projected enrollment studies, 1954 December-1955 January (Box 6)
  - Tallies, 1950-1957 (Box 7)
  - Undergraduate Men Enrollment, 1946-1950 (Box 7)
  - University Enrollment, 1850-1943 (Box 7)
  - Women's College Statistical Studies: Estimate of Future Enrollment, 1956 (Box 7)
  - Exchange Visitor Program, 1950-1964 (Box 7)
  - Academic Salaries: Comparative Study, 1955-1957 (Box 7)
  - Academic Acceleration, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Beta Omega Sigma, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Brief in Support of the Application for Authority to Commence Construction, 1951 (Box 7)
  - Central Committee: War Emergency, 1950 (Box 7)
  - Class and Lab Space (Box 7)
  - College Entrance Board: Examination Data (Box 7)
  - Commencement, 1967 (Box 7)
  - Committee on the Central Records Office (Box 7)
  - Degrees Conferred by Duke University/Trinity College, 1853-1955 (Box 7)
  - Digital Computer: Research and Training Program (Box 7)
  - Divinity School: Staff Analysis (Box 7)
  - Duke Hospital: Comparative Statement, 1958-1959 and Budget, 1959-1960 (Box 7)
  - Engineering College Staff, 1954-1956 (Box 7)
  - English Usage Committee (Box 7)
  - Faculty Advisors, 1953-1954 (Box 7)
  - Correspondence of Dean Alan K. Manchester, 1951-1955 (Box 7)
  - Hamilton's Address: The Past and Future of the Duke University Chapter of the American Association of University Professors, 1952 (Box 7)
  - Memorandum: The Development of a Corporate Trinity College, 1963 March 22 (Box 7)
  - Memorandum: South Atlantic Quarterly, 1955 (Box 7)
  - Memorandum: Work Papers on Trinity College, 1963 (Box 7)
  - National Committee on the Emeriti, Inc: List of Deceased Instructional and Administrative Staff, 1940-1958 (Box 8)
  - Faculty Data Sheets - A-Z (Box 8)
  - Faculty Data Sheets: Deceased, Retired, Resigned - A-Z (Box 8)
  - One Box Faculty Data Cards (Box 8)
  - Office, Classroom and Seminar Assignments, 1953-1955 (Box 9)
  - Office of Registrar (Box 9)
  - Probation Form Letters (Box 9)
  - Remedial Courses (Box 9)
  - Salary Scale by Rank, 1948-1953 (Box 9)
  - Study of Absences for Juniors, 1957 Fall (Box 9)
  - Study on Intra-College Transfers (Box 9)
  - University Committee on Planning and Development (Box 9)
  - Federal Security Agency: Office of Education, 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous Questionnaires, 1950-1958 (Box 9)
  - National Science Foundation, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Secondary Schools, 1950-1955 (Box 9)
  - Unprocessed Questionnaires, circa 1950-1951 (Box 9)
  - Academic Standards Committee, 1956-1964 (Box 9)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Scholarship Programs and Grants-in-Aid, 1961-1962 (Box 9)
  - Analysis of Overloads, 1956-1957 RESTRICTED (Box 9)
  - Angier B. Duke Memorial Scholarship, 1948-1952 RESTRICTED (Box 9)
  - Annual Report of the Freshman/Sophomore Office, 1952-1956 (Box 9)
  - Budget Material of Trinity College, 1956-1964 RESTRICTED (Box 9)
  - Class Meetings, 1953-1954 (Box 9)
  - Committee on Foreign Students (Box 9)
  - Committee on Graduation with Distinction, 1955-1964 (Box 9)
  - Curriculum Committee, 1949-1964 (Box 9)
  - Dean of Freshmen: Report of the President, 1934-1950 (Box 9)
  - Dean of Undergraduate Studies: Description of Functions (Box 9)
  - Clippings: Administrative and Professional Activities, 1934-1970 (Box 9)
  - Administrative Reorganization Following the Appointment of Dr. Gross, 1949 (Box 9)
  - Dean of Undergraduate Studies: Report to the President, 1949-1956 (Box 9)
  - Freshman Handbook, 1954-1955 (Box 9)
  - Freshman Office, 1949-1950 (Box 9)
  - Freshman Traditions, Early 1950s (Box 9)
  - National Defense Student Loan Program, 1958 (Box 9)
  - Nursing and Medical School Scholarship Committees (Box 9)
  - Origins and Early Development of the Housemaster System: Address made on 1963 September 11 (Box 9)
  - Pre-Medical Course of Study, 1950-1953 (Box 9)
  - Quality Point Ratio: Tables, 1957 (Box 9)
  - Questionnaire in Preparation for Consultation Visit on Program Improvement Regulations, 1952-1955 (Box 9)
  - School of Nursing: Accreditation by the National League for Nursing (Box 9)
  - School of Nursing: Committee to Study Problems Leading to a Master's Degree In Nursing (Box 9)
  - School of Nursing, 1953-1963 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 10)
  - Semester Hour Load for Freshmen and Course Enrollment, 1957-1958 (Box 10)
  - Student Loan Policy Committee, 1955-1964 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 10)
  - Subcommittee on Financial Aid and Scholarships and University Committee on Admissions, 1962-1963 (Box 10)
  - Meetings of Undergraduate Deans with Marcus Hobbs, 1960-1963 (Box 10)
  - Meetings of Undergraduate Deans with Harold Lewis, 1963-1964 (Box 10)
  - Organization, Orientation and Installation of New Administration and Staff Meetings, 1956-1957 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 10)
  - Report to the President, 1956-1964 (Box 10)
  - Spielgerger Project on Underachievers, 1962 February (Box 10)
  - Staff Meetings and Miscellaneous Matters, 1957-1964 *Contains Restricted Information (Box 10)
  - Undergraduate Distribution by Classes, 1924-1936 (Box 10)
  - University Council Committee and Committee on Grading Standards, 1960 (Box 10)
  - University Faculty, 1951-1961 (Box 10)
  - University Scholarship Committee, 1951-1964 RESTRICTED (Box 10)
  - Academic Guide 1960 Edition (Box 10)
  - Brochure on Advising and Counseling, 1966 (Box 10)
  - Advanced Placement Program, 1957-1965 (Box 10)
  - Sophomore Course Card and Writing, 1960-1963 (Box 10)
  - Cut Probation Letters and List of Students, 1957-1959 (Box 10)
  - Committee on Faculty Advising, 1959-1960 (Box 10)
  - Faculty Advising System: General, 1956-1965 (Box 10)
  - Special Advising Program, 1957-1963 (Box 11)
  - Daedalus Program, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Professor Gross' Distinguished Professor Seminar, 1965 (Box 11)
  - Upperclass Experimental Dormitory Group, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Dormitory Experiments, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Residential House H File, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Advanced Placement Program, 1955-1956 (Box 11)
  - Faculty Associate Program, 1961-1964 (Box 11)
  - Freshman Advising Council, 1953-1955 (Box 11)
  - Freshman Tutorial Program, 1964-1966 (Box 11)
  - Faculty Advisers Form Letters, 1960-1961 (Box 11)
  - Faculty Adviser Reference Manuals, Handbooks, 1952-1964 (Box 11)
  - Form Letters, 1956-1960 (Box 11)
  - Academic Guide, 1961-1965 (Box 11)
  - Faculty Advisers: Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 11)
  - Dinner-Discussions, 1959-1962 (Box 11)
  - Freshman-Sophomore Colloquia Seminars, 1963-1964 (Box 11)
  - Special Advising Students, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Special Advising Discussions, 1962-1963 (Box 11)
  - Special Sections, Selection of Students, 1962-1964 (Box 11)
  - Honors Program, 1957-1965 (Box 11)
  - Independent Study, 1961-1962 (Box 11)
  - Reading Out of Courses, 1958-1964 (Box 11)
  - Minimum Requirements for Continuation, 1961 (Box 11)
  - Pre-Medical Information, 1955-1964 (Box 11)
  - Special Advising Program Participants, 1958-1959 (Box 11)
  - Summer Reading, 1963 (Box 11)
  - Organization of UFC Restudy by Committee, 1962-1964 (Box 11)
  - Undergraduate Regulations Brochure, 1966 (Box 11)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1949-1961 (Box 11)
  - Fraternity Averages [Freshmen Pledges], 1945-1969 (Box 12)
  - Fraternity Activities [Officers, Memberships, Activities], 1950-1971 (Box 13)
  - Alpha Kappa Psi, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Alpha Phi Omega, 1955-1969 (Box 14)
  - ASDU Minutes, 1967-1968 (Box 14)
  - Blood Drives, 1953-1954 (Box 14)
  - Campus Organization Officers, 1968-1969 (Box 14)
  - Chronicle, 1958-1962 (Box 14)
  - Constitutions: AIH, ARC, Inter-Government Council, 1967-1968 (Box 14)
  - Duke Forum, 1964 (Box 14)
  - Dean Cox: Chapter House Results, 1966 (Box 14)
  - Eta Kappa Nu, 1952-1961 (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Miscellaneous Commentaries on Various Aspects of Frat. Life, circa 1948 (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Other Schools, 1952-1960 (Box 14)
  - Booklets: Responsibilities of Fraternities Concerning Records on their Membership, undated (Box 14)
  - Fraternity Correspondence, 1957-1968 (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Fees and Dues, 1957-1958 (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Social Probation Rules, undated (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Depledged and Inactive Letters, 1963-1968 (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Membership, 1967-1971 (Box 14)
  - Fraternity: Rush Rules, Pledging and Initiation, 1951-1961 (Box 14)
  - Freshman Advisory Council, 1955-1964 (Box 14)
  - Freshman-Sophomore Field Day, 1950-1961 (Box 14)
  - Homecoming Steering Committee, 1955-1956 (Box 14)
  - Honor Codes and Honor System, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Honorary Societies, 1948-1962 (Box 14)
  - Hoof-n-Horn, 1951-1958 (Box 14)
  - Independent Dormitory Council, 1952-1959 (Box 14)
  - Independents Society, undated (Box 14)
  - IFC Constitution, By-Laws and Rush Rules, 1951-1960 (Box 14)
  - Greek Week, 1953-1964 (Box 14)
  - IFC: Correspondence, 1962-1966 (Box 14)
  - IFC Pledge Rules and IFC Booklets and Rush, 1962-1963 (Box 14)
  - IFC Penal Code, 1961-1962 (Box 14)
  - IFC, 1967-1968 (Box 14)
  - Intramural Program, 1960 (Box 14)
  - Judicial Board: Chronicle Articles, 1964-1965 (Box 14)
  - Living Group Officers, 1971-1972 (Box 14)
  - Men's Student Government Association, MSGA, 1950-1965 (Box 14)
  - MSGA Constitutions, 1960-1963 (Box 14)
  - MSGA Minutes, 1966-1968 (Box 14)
  - MSGA Penal Code, 1957-1961 (Box 14)
  - National Interfraternity Conference, 1955-1969 (Box 14)
  - National Interfraternity Council Publications, 1969 (Box 14)
  - NIC Constitution and By-Laws, 1968 (Box 14)
  - NC Interfraternity Council Workshop, 1956 (Box 14)
  - PEP Board, 1952-1957 (Box 14)
  - Radio Station: WDBS, 1957 (Box 14)
  - Shoe and Slipper and Joe College, undated (Box 14)
  - Special Events, undated (Box 14)
  - Spofford Memorial Sword, 1953 (Box 14)
  - Student Union, 1963 (Box 14)
  - Traditions Board, 1954-1958 (Box 14)
  - Young Americans for Freedom, Inc., 1966 (Box 14)
  - YMCA, 1948-1963 (Box 14)
  - Baldridge Evaluations, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Baldridge Reading Services, 1964 (Box 15)
  - Campus Community Council, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Coed New Curriculum Project, 1970 (Box 15)
  - College Dean's Group Meetings, 1967-1968 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence with Taylor Cole Unclassified, 1967 (Box 15)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Continuing Education, 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Curriculum for Engineering Students Class of 1973 and Beyond, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Deans: their duties, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Deans of Arts and Sciences Meetings, 1964-1967 (Box 15)
  - Dean's Report to the President, 1960-1966 (Box 15)
  - Trinity College Self-Study, 1965 (Box 15)
  - University Faculty Meeting, 1970-1971 (Box 15)
  - Faculty Fellows of Trinity College, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
  - Federation Business, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Fraternities, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Freshman Orientation, 1965-1967 (Box 15)
  - Grade Distribution Study, 1964-1965 (Box 15)
  - Honors Masters Program, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
  - Honors Special Curricular Offerings Brochure, 1962-1967 (Box 15)
  - Internal Development and Alumni Relations Council, 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Correspondence with Douglas Knight Unclassified, 1964-1966 (Box 15)
  - Learning Disabilities Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 15)
  - Leave of Absence Policy, 1969 (Box 15)
  - Loyalty Fund, 1970 (Box 15)
  - MSGA Correspondence Unclassified, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - MSGA Minutes, 1966-1967 (Box 15)
  - President, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Publications Board, 1970 (Box 15)
  - Residential Governance Study Committee, 1971 (Box 15)
  - Southern Association of Colleges and Schools Self-Study and Committee Visitation, 1965-1966 (Box 15)
  - Sexuality-Survey-Human Dean Griffith's Office, 1971 (Box 15)
  - TC and WC Joint Staff Meeting, 1971-1972 (Box 15)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council, 1963-1966 (Box 15)
  - Undergraduate Faculty Council Memorials on Death of Faculty Members, 1952-1964 (Box 15)